Finding Aid for Gunnar Birkerts and Associates, 1960-2014
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Tougaloo College, Tougaloo, Mississippi 1963-1981, 638 drawings; 3 linear feet
  - Tougaloo College Library
    - Tougaloo College Library Drawings
      - Construction Documents
        - Architectural Drawings. Pencil on vellum drawings 10/30/1969, except as noted
          - Lower Level Plan (A-2). Revised 10/13/1970 (Map-case 6, Folder 9)
          - First Floor Plan (A-3). Revised 10/13/1970 (Map-case 6, Folder 9)
          - Second Floor Plan (A-4) (Map-case 6, Folder 9)
          - Third Floor Plan (A-5) (Map-case 6, Folder 9)
          - Roof Plan and Details (A-6) (Map-case 6, Folder 9)
          - Lower Level and First Floor Reflected Ceiling Plans and Ceiling Details (A-7) (Map-case 6, Folder 9)
          - Second Floor Reflected Ceiling Plan (A-8) (Map-case 6, Folder 9)
          - Third Floor Reflected Ceiling Plan (A-9) (Map-case 6, Folder 9)
          - Exterior Elevations (A-10) (Map-case 6, Folder 9)
          - Exterior Elevations and Building Sections (A-11) (Map-case 6, Folder 9)
          - Building Sections (A-12) (Map-case 6, Folder 9)
          - Core Plans and Elevation Details (A-13). Revised 10/13/1970 (Map-case 6, Folder 9)
          - Building Sections and Details (A-14) (Map-case 6, Folder 9)
          - Construction Details (A-15) (Map-case 6, Folder 9)
          - Stair Details (A-16) (Map-case 6, Folder 9)
          - Door Details and Miscellaneous Details (A-17). Revised 10/13/1970 (Map-case 6, Folder 9)
          - Interior Elevations and Details (A-18) (Map-case 6, Folder 9)
        - Structural Drawings by Robert M. Darvas and Associates, Consulting Structural Engineers. Pencil on vellum drawings 10/30/1969 except as noted
          - Caisson Plan and Column Details (S-1) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Basement Plan (S-2) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - First Floor Plan (S-3) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Second Floor Plan (S-4) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Third Floor Plan (S-5) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Roof Plans (S-6) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - West Core Plans and Section (S-7) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - East Core Plans and Section (S-8) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Stair Details (S-9) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Stair Details (S-10) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Stair Details (S-10A) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Precast Beam Details (S-11) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Precast Column Capitals (S-12) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Precast Wall Panels and Cores (S-13) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Precast Wall Panels and Cores (S-14) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Precast Wall Panels (S-15) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Revised Beam B-1 on Line "O," Third Floor (S-16). Sepia print 08/20/1970 (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
        - Mechanical and Electrical Drawings by Hoyem, Basso, Adams, and Martin, Consulting Engineers. Sepia prints 12/12/1969 revised 8/7/70, except as noted
          - Mechanical and Electrical Site Plan (ME-1). Revised 07/01/1970 (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Mechanical Basement Plan (M-1). (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Mechanical First Floor Plan and Schedule (M-2) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Mechanical Second Floor Plan (M-3) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Mechanical Third Floor Plan and Detail (M-4) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Plumbing West Core Plans and Details (M-5) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Plumbing East Core Plans and Details (M-6) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Mechanical West Core Plans (M-7) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Mechanical East Core Plans (M-8) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Mechanical Boiler Room Plan and Schematics (M-9) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Lighting and Power Basement Plan (E-1) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Lighting and Power First Floor Plan (E-2) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Lighting and Power Second Floor Plan (E-3) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Lighting and Power Third Floor Plan (E-4) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
          - Electrical Riser Diagram (E-5) (Map-case 6, Folder 10)
      - Shop Drawings
        - Blue-line prints
          - Elevator Drawings and Charts by Dover Elevator Co. Ten prints undated (Map-case 6, Folder 11)
          - Precast Capitals Details (CD1) by Jackson Ready-Mix Concrete. Approved 06/23/1970 by Robert M. Darvas and Associates (Map-case 6, Folder 11)
          - Erection Plans (E1-E6) by Jackson Ready-Mix Concrete. Six prints, approved for fabrication 10/05/1970 (Map-case 6, Folder 11)
          - Concrete Design Data and Details (D1-D4) by Jackson Ready-Mix Concrete. Four prints, approved for fabrication 10/05/1970 (Map-case 6, Folder 11)
          - Precast Concrete Details, Plan and Section of Paving Units by Jackson Stone Co. Accepted 01/18/1971 by Gunnar Birkerts and Associates (Map-case 6, Folder 11)
          - Plan and Sections by Jackson Ready-Mix Concrete. Undated (Map-case 6, Folder 11)
  - Tougaloo College Dormitories "A" and "B"
    Contractor: Winston A. Burnett Construction Company
    Agreement Date: October 24, 1966
    Earliest Dated Drawing: October 25, 1965
    Latest Dated Construction Drawing: July 1, 1970
    Tougaloo College Dormitories A and B are the second and third buildings constructed on campus in accordance with the 1965 Master Plan, which emphasized the close relationship between the residential, social and intellectual life of the students. When a preliminary brick and block design for Dormitory A of April, 1968, was estimated to be too expensive and discarded, a precast, concrete, bearing wall scheme was designed and accepted on 7/25/69. An innovative, Waldschmidt System, portable, construction plant was erected on site to expeditiously produce the precast, structural members for both the Dormitories and Library. Mr. Birkerts uses parallel rows of giant, concrete caissons to penetrate the unstable Yazoo clay and support the linear Dormitory buildings with pedestrian walkways underneath. He provides for both the privacy and social interaction of students by grouping dormitory rooms around common lounges. Although the multi-level Master Plan was never completely implemented, the Dormitories and Library are testimony to the flexibility and expandability of Mr. Birkerts' visionary design.
    The Tougaloo College Dormitories A and B subseries combines 1.5 linear feet of textual materials, which chronologically document the design and construction of the buildings, and 246 architectural drawings, which graphically illuminate the phases of the architectural design process. The pairing of the narrative and visual records gives design students, preservationists and other researchers a thorough understanding of the evolution of these buildings.
    Within the textual records, the undated paper by Gunnar Birkerts and Associates entitled, "The Development of A Construction Process for College Buildings Utilizing Industrial and Plant Construction Techniques," describes the innovative Waldschmidt System for fabricating concrete structural members on the site. The essay further discusses the challenges of meeting budget and scheduling demands over the course of this project. Researchers can also compare the written "Specifications" for the discarded, 1968 brick and block scheme with the "Specifications" for the 1969 precast, concrete, bearing wall scheme, which was used in the construction of the Dormitories. Also of special interest are the 126 8x10" black and white photographs of Dormitories A and B which document their monthly construction progress.
    The 246 drawings which make up the visual records for the Dormitories A and B subseries include one folder of early "Schematic Design" drawings from 1965, four folders of "Design Development" drawings and four folders of "Construction Documents" for both the 1968 and 1969 schemes, giving the researcher a view of the entire architectural design process. Drawings from all phases are both original pencil and ink on vellum documents and prints with original annotations or drawings on them. The ink on vellum "Design Development Presentation Drawings" are especially beautiful. The visual "Construction Documents," which correspond directly to the written "Specifications" in the textual records, show both the unbuilt, brick and block scheme which was discarded due to cost, and the precast, concrete, bearing wall scheme, which was built using the innovative Waldschmidt System.
    - Tougaloo College Dormitories "A" and "B" Architectural Records
      - Tougaloo College Dormitory "A" Architectural Records
        - HUD Construction Financing 1965-1969 (Box 5)
        - HUD Correspondence, Documents and Information 1967-1972 (Box 5)
        - Preliminary Dormitory "A" Specifications 11/29/1966, 09/16/1967 (Box 5)
        - Specifications 02/26/1968 (Box 5)
        - Specifications (Brick and Block Scheme, unbuilt) 06/29/1968
          - Table of Contents and Bidding Requirements (Box 5)
          - General (HUD) and Supplementary General Conditions (Box 5)
          - General Requirements and Site Work (Box 5)
          - Concrete, Masonry and Carpentry (Box 5)
          - Moisture Protection and Doors, Windows and Glass (Box 5)
          - Finishes and Specialties (Box 5)
          - Mechanical and Electrical (Box 5)
        - Addenda 1968 (Box 5)
        - List of Subcontractors 1970 (Box 5)
      - Tougaloo College Dormitories "A" and "B" Architectural Records
        - "The Development of A Construction Process for College Buildings Utilizing Industrial and Plant Construction Techniques" by Gunnar Birkerts & Associates undated (Box 5)
        - Specifications (Precast Concrete Bearing Wall Scheme) 07/25/1969
          - Table of Contents and Bidding Requirements (Box 5)
          - General Conditions (HUD) and General Requirements (Box 5)
          - Site Work and Concrete (Box 5)
          - Metals, Carpentry and Moisture Protection (Box 5)
          - Doors, Windows and Glass and Finishes (Box 5)
          - Specialties, Mechanical and Electrical (Box 5)
        - Bulletins #1-7 1969-1972 (Box 5)
        - Materials and Finishes 1970 (Box 5)
        - Furniture Schedules, Specifications and Correspondence 1970-1973 (Box 5)
        - Dorms "A" and "B" Change Orders, #1A-2A 1970-1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "A" Change Orders, # 3A-11A 1970-1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Change Orders, #3B-9B 1971-1972 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "A" Construction Reports, #1-6 1970-1971 (Box 5)
        - Maxwell-Spencer-Hust Monthly Reports #1-22 1970-1971 (Box 5)
        - Winston A. Burnett Construction Company Requisitions #1-21 1970-1972 (Box 5)
        - Architect's Certificates of Payment for Winston A. Burnett Company Engineering Design 1970-1972 (Box 5)
        - Correspondence In from Winston A. Burnett Construction Company
          - 1969 (Box 5)
          - January-August, 1970 (Box 5)
          - August-December, 1970 (Box 5)
          - 1971 (Box 5)
          - 1972-1973 (Box 5)
        - Guarantees and Warranties 1972 (Box 5)
        - Litigation Correspondence and Support Documents
          - 1970-1974 (Box 5)
          - 1977-1981 (Box 5)
    - Tougaloo College Dormitories Photographs
      - Construction Photographs of Dormitory "A," 1970. Eleven 8x10-inch black and white prints and seventeen negatives (Box 5)
        - Dorm "A." One print 04/03/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "A." One print 06/04/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "A." One print 06/30/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "A." One print 07/31/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "A." One print 08/31/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "A" Looking West and Northwest. Three prints 10/05/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "A" Looking Northwest. Two prints 10/31/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "A." One print 12/07/1970 (Box 5)
      - Construction Photographs of Dormitory "A," 1971. Twenty-two 8x10-inch black and white prints and twenty negatives
        - Dorm "A." One print 01/15/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "A." Looking West, One print 01/15/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "A" Looking West and Northwest. Three prints 02/15/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "A" Looking Northwest. Two prints 03/11/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "A" Looking North. One print 04/07/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "A" Looking North. Two prints 04/09/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "A" Looking North, East, Northeast and Northwest. Five prints 05/05/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "A" Looking East and West. Five prints 06/03/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "A" Looking West, Lost Panels. One print 06/03/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "A" Walkway. One print, 7/16/71. (Box 5)
      - Construction Photographs of Dormitory "B," 1970. Forty-three 8x10-inch black and white prints and fifty-one negatives
        - Dorm "B." Two prints 04/03/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B." Five prints 06/04/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B." Two prints 06/30/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B." One print 07/31/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B." Two prints 08/31/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" and Library from Holmes Hall. Two prints 08/31/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B." Two prints 10/05/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Looking East, West and Northwest. Five prints, 10/5/70. (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Looking West, Southwest and Northwest. Three prints 10/31/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B." Five prints 10/31/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B." One print 11/06/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Beams, One print 11/06/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B." One print 11/07/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B." One print 12/07/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" North and West Views. Two prints 12/07/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Walkway. One print 12/07/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" First Panels. Three prints 12/11/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Stairway Looking Southwest. One print 12/11/1970 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Walkway Detail. Three prints 12/11/1970 (Box 5)
      - Construction Photographs of Dormitory "B," 1971. Thirty-seven 8x10-inch black and white prints and forty negatives
        - Dorm "B" Looking North, South and East. Three prints 01/15/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Stairway Looking North. One print 01/15/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Erection Procedures, Preparing Supports. Two prints 02/15/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Support and Leveling Blocks. One print 02/15/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Erection Procedures, Exterior Panel on Steel, Leveling Blocks. One print 02/15/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Erection Procedures. One print 02/15/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Erection Procedures, Leveling Blocks. One print 02/15/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Ready to Erect. One print 02/15/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Spalling Cap. Two prints 02/15/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Looking North. One print 02/15/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Wide Grout Seam. One print 02/15/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Flaking Grout. One print 02/15/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Looking North, South and East. Five prints 03/11/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Erection Chips. One print 03/11/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Looking North, South and West. Four prints 04/09/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Looking North, South and West. Four prints 05/05/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Looking South and West. Two prints 06/03/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Walkway. Two prints 07/16/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Windows. One print 07/16/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" Looking South. One print 07/16/1971 (Box 5)
        - Dorm "B" with View of Project. One print 07/16/1971 (Box 5)
      - Construction Photographs of Wall Panels, 1970. Thirteen 8x10-inch black and white prints and eleven negatives (Box 6)
        - Dorm Wall Panel. Three prints 10/05/1970 (Box 6)
        - Rejected Beam. Two prints 10/05/1970 (Box 6)
        - Second Try, Double Beam. Two prints 10/05/1970 (Box 6)
        - Panel Problems. Six prints 11/06/1970 (Box 6)
      - Construction Photographs of Burnett Plant, 1970-1971. Two 8x10-inch black and white prints and one negative
        - Burnett Plant from East, One print 08/31/1970 (Box 6)
        - Burnett Plant Looking North, One print 05/05/1971 (Box 6)
      - As-Built Photographs of Dormitories and Library. Sixteen 31/2x5-inch black and white prints, 8/78, and twelve 8x10-inch black and white negatives undated (Box 6)
    - Tougaloo College Library and Dormitories "A" and "B" Architectural Records
      - Allen, Gerald. "The Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis and the Dormitories and Library Buildings for Tougaloo College." Architectural Record. November, 1973, 105-116 (Box 6)
      - Agreements 1966-1972 (Box 6)
      - Architect's Project Representative Information (Box 6)
      - Correspondence In from Tougaloo College
        - 1965-1967 (Box 6)
        - 1968-1969 (Box 6)
        - 1970 (Box 6)
        - 1971-1974 (Box 6)
      - Invoicing and Contractual Correspondence 1968-1973 (Box 6)
      - Memoranda 1971-1975 (Box 6)
      - Maxwell-Spencer-Hust, Consulting Engineers, Brochure (Box 6)
      - Inspection Reports by Maxwell-Spencer-Hust
        - February-June, 1970 (Box 6)
        - July-December, 1970. (Box 6)
        - January-March, 1971 (Box 6)
        - April-June, 1971. (Box 6)
        - July-September, 1971 (Box 6)
        - October 1971-November, 1971 (Box 6)
      - Correspondence
        - In from Smith & Sanders, Inc., Consulting Engineers 1965-1970 (Box 6)
        - In from Hoyem, Basso & Adams, Inc., Consulting Engineers.
          - 1965-1969 (Box 6)
          - 1970 (Box 6)
        - In from Hoyem Associates, Incorporated
          - 1971 (Box 6)
          - 1972-1977 (Box 6)
        - Out 1969-1971 (Box 6)
        - Out 1972-1979 (Box 6)
      - Sculpture Court Project 1976-1978 (Box 6)
    - Tougaloo College Dormitory "A" Drawings
      - Design Development Drawings
        - Pencil or ink drawings on velum
          - Title Page. Undated (Map-case 7, Folder 1)
          - Building Location Plan, Floor Plans, Elevations, Details and Sections (P1-P12). Nine pencil on vellum drawings and three pencil drawings on reverse sepia prints undated (Map-case 7, Folder 1)
          - Roof Plan. 10/03/1966 (Map-case 7, Folder 1)
          - Floor Plans, Elevations and Sections. Seven drawings undated (Map-case 7, Folder 1)
          - Typical Upper Floor Mechanical Plan (PM-1). Pencil drawing on reverse sepia print undated (Map-case 7, Folder 1)
          - Power Plan and Equipment Layout Plan (PM-2). Undated (Map-case 7, Folder 1)
      - Construction Documents
        - Architectural Drawings for Brick and Block Design (Not Built)
          - Site Plan (A-1). Pencil on vellum drawing 06/29/1968 (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
          - Floor Plans and Elevations (A-2). Pencil drawing on sepia print 04/15/1968 (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
          - Floor Plans and Elevations (A-2). Pencil on vellum drawing 06/29/1968 (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
          - First Floor Plan, Typical House (A-3). Pencil drawing on sepia print 04/15/1968 (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
          - First Floor Plan, Typical House (A-3). Pencil on vellum drawing 06/29/1968 (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
          - Second Floor Plan, Typical House (A-4). Pencil drawing on sepia print 04/15/1968 (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
          - Second Floor Plan, Typical House (A-4). Pencil on vellum drawing 06/29/1968 (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
          - Reflected Ceiling Plans (A-5). Pencil drawing on sepia print 04/15/1968 (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
          - Reflected Ceiling Plans (A-5). Pencil on vellum drawing 06/29/1968 (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
          - Sections and Stair Details (A-6). "Void" in pencil on sepia print 04/15/1968 (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
          - Sections and Stair Details (A-6). Pencil on vellum drawing 06/29/1968 (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
          - Door Details and Miscellaneous Details (A-7). Ink markings on sepia print 04/15/1968 (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
          - Door Details (A-7). Pencil on vellum drawing 06/29/1968 (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
          - Partial Elevation and Exterior Wall Details (A-8). Pencil on vellum drawing 04/15/1968 (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
          - Partial Elevation and Exterior Wall Details (A-8). "Void" in ink on sepia print. 04/15/1968 (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
          - Wall Sections (A-8). Pencil on vellum drawing 06/29/1968 (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
          - Exterior Wall Details (A-9). Pencil on vellum drawing 04/15/1968 (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
          - Exterior Wall Details (A-9). "Void" in ink on sepia print 04/15/1968 (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
          - Walkway Sections (A-9). Pencil on vellum drawing 06/29/1968 (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
          - Miscellaneous Details (A-10). Pencil on vellum drawing 04/15/1968 (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
          - Miscellaneous Details (A-10). "Void" in ink on sepia print 04/15/1968 (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
          - Student Room Elevations (A-11). Pencil on vellum drawing 04/15/1968 (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
          - Student Room Elevations (A-11). "Void" in ink on sepia print 04/15/1968 (Map-case 7, Folder 2)
        - Structural Drawings for Brick and Block Design (Not Built) by Robert M. Darvas and Associates, Consulting Structural Engineers. Pencil on vellum drawings 06/29/1968
          - Foundation Plan and Details (S-1) (Map-case 7, Folder 3)
          - Walkway, Stairs and Details (S-2) (Map-case 7, Folder 3)
          - First Floor Plan and Details (S-3) (Map-case 7, Folder 3)
          - Second Floor Plan and Details (S-4) (Map-case 7, Folder 3)
          - Roof Plan and Details (S-5) (Map-case 7, Folder 3)
          - West End Stairway Details (S-6) (Map-case 7, Folder 3)
        - Mechanical and Electrical Drawings for Brick and Block Design (Not Built). Sepia prints with pencil notations 04/15/1968 revised, 06/05/1968
          - Dormitory Floor Plans (M-1) (Map-case 7, Folder 3)
          - Typical House, Plumbing Plans (M-2) (Map-case 7, Folder 3)
          - Typical House, Heating, Air Conditioning Plan (M-3) (Map-case 7, Folder 3)
          - Riser Diagram and Details (M-4) (Map-case 7, Folder 3)
          - Dormitory Floor Plans (E-1) (Map-case 7, Folder 3)
          - Typical House Floor Plans (E-2) (Map-case 7, Folder 3)
          - Riser Diagram (E-3) (Map-case 7, Folder 3)
    - Tougaloo College Dormitories "A" and "B" Drawings
      - Schematic Design Drawings
        - Preliminary Dormitory Studies, based on Room Arrangement Study by Gunnar Birkerts and Associates, 10/25/65. Thirteen ink drawings of floor plans, elevations and sections on black-line prints (Map-case 7, Folder 4)
        - [Elevations], untitled. Two pencil on vellum drawings undated (Map-case 7, Folder 4)
        - [Room Plans and Axonometric], untitled. Pencil and ink drawings on sepia and reverse sepia prints, pieced together on one sheet undated (Map-case 7, Folder 4)
        - [Floor Plans and Sections], untitled, Ink on vellum drawing undated (Map-case 7, Folder 4)
      - Design Development Drawings
        - Pencil and ink drawings on tracing paper, undated, except as noted
          - [Site Plan], untitled (Map-case 7, Folder 5)
          - [Elevations], untitled. Three drawings (Map-case 7, Folder 5)
          - Three Conditions: Typical Student Room, Lounge, End Wall (Map-case 7, Folder 5)
          - First Level Pod Plan (Map-case 7, Folder 5)
          - Dormitory "A" Section at Stairs (Map-case 7, Folder 5)
          - Dormitory "B" Section at Stairs (Map-case 7, Folder 5)
          - [Section], untitled (Map-case 7, Folder 5)
          - Door Locations at Stair, Faculty Housing. 07/22/1969 (Map-case 7, Folder 5)
          - [Section Isometric Showing Structural System], untitled. Two drawings (Map-case 7, Folder 5)
          - [Joint and Flashing Details], untitled. Seven drawings (Map-case 7, Folder 5)
          - Typical Exterior Detail (Map-case 7, Folder 5)